A Guide to the M. Patton Echols papers, 1970-1972
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
M. Patton Echols papers, 1970-1972
Library of Virginia
53652
.975 cubic feet (3 boxes).
M. Patton Echols
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Before serving the materials, Library reference archivists must check the files for privacy protected and confidential information. Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800 and 2.2-3705.1-8.
Acquisition Information
Gift of R. Carter Echols, Arlington, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Marion Patton Echols was born 1 October 1925 in Oahu, Hawaii, to Marion Patton Echols, a military officer, and Mary Patterson McArthur Echols. He graduated from the Virginia Military Institute in 1945 and began working as an engineer for the York Corporation. Echols was inducted into the army in 1951 during the Korean War. After the war, Echols served in the Reserves, eventually reaching the rank of lieutenant colonel. Returning to the York Corporation he was transferred to work in Washington D.C. Echols attended law school at George Washington University at night, receiving his degree in 1958. He began practicing law in Arlington County, Virginia. Echols was elected to represent Arlington in the Virginia state senate in 1969, serving one term. In 1973 he was the Republican candidate for attorney general. Echols married Susanne Stokes 10 November 1956 in Washington D.C., and they had four children. He married Beth McLaren in September 2005. Echols died in Fairfax County, Virginia, 26 July 2012, and was buried in the Echols family plot in the University of Virginia Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Constituent correspondence, 1970-1972, sent to Virginia state senator M. Patton Echols (1925-2012) of Arlington County, discussing legislation in the Virginia General Assembly during the 1970 and 1971 sessions, including abortion, the new state constitution, education, prescription drugs, taxation, and other topics; as well as individuals asking for assistance.
Contents List
- Constituent correspondence, A 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Constituent correspondence, A 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constituent correspondence, Abortion, House Bill 495 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Constituent correspondence, B 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Constituent correspondence, B 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constituent correspondence, C 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Constituent correspondence, C 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Constituent correspondence, D 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Constituent correspondence, D-E 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Constituent correspondence, E-F 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Constituent correspondence, F-G 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Constituent correspondence, G 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Constituent correspondence, H-J 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Constituent correspondence, H-J 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Constituent correspondence, K-L 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Constituent correspondence, K-L 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Constituent correspondence, M 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Constituent correspondence, M 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Constituent correspondence, N-O 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Constituent correspondence, N, P 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Constituent correspondence, P 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Constituent correspondence, Pill (prescription drugs), House Bill 271 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Constituent correspondence, Q-R 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Constituent correspondence, R 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Constituent correspondence, S 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Constituent correspondence, S 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Constituent correspondence, T-V 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Constituent correspondence, T-V 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Constituent correspondence, W 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Constituent correspondence, W 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Constituent correspondence, Y-Z 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Constituent correspondence, Y-Z 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Tags, address labels (Box 3, Folder 8)